-想听懂我要讲的故事
- To understand what I'm about to tell you,
你得有所准备
You need to do something first.
你得相信一些不可思议的事
You need to believe in the impossible.
你能做到吗 很好
Can you do that? Good.
看到那红色的影子了吗
You see that red blur?
那是我
That's me.
那也是
That too.
还是我
There I am again.
我叫巴里 艾伦
My name is barry allen.
我是世上速度最快的人
I am the fastest man alive.
14年前
我的故事很简单
My story is pretty simple.
我一生一直都在奔跑
My whole life, I have been running.
通常是因为被欺负
Usually from bullies.
有时我逃脱了
Sometimes I escaped.
有时被逮着
Sometimes I did not.
- 告诉我发生了什么
- Tell me what happened.
- 那些家伙欺负人
- Those guys were picking on kids
就是因为他们觉得不爽
Just 'cause they thought they weren't cool.
-这不对 -我明白了
It wasn't right. - I know.
- 我想该怪我跑得不够快 -不
- I guess I wasn't fast enough. - No.
你有一颗善良的心 巴里
You have such a good heart, barry.
善良之心比飞毛腿好得多
And it's better to have a good heart than fast legs.
-有人在家吗 我回来了
- Hello. I'm home.
- 巴里打架了 -噢 是吗
- Barry got into a fight. - Oh, yeah?
- 而且打赢了
- And he won.
- 噢 干得漂亮 猛男
- Ah, way to go, slugger.
噢 我是说 不许再打架了
Oh, and uh, no more fighting.
嗯 嗯
Mm-mm.
- 但在那晚之后
- But after that night,
我奔跑是为了逃避一些更恐怖的东西
I was running from something much scarier.
一些我永远无法解释的东西 - 亨利 亨利
Something I could never explain. - Henry! Henry!
- 一些不可思议的东西
- Something impossible.
- 救命
- Help!
- 妈妈 妈妈 - 巴里 别过来
- Mom! Mom! - Barry, don't!
- 妈妈 - 别让他碰你
- Mom! - Don't let him touch you!
妈妈
Mom!
- 妈妈
- Mom!
- 诺拉 - 呆远点
- Nora! - Stay back!
诺拉 坚持住
Nora, hold on!
- 跑 巴里 快跑
- Run, barry, run!
- 妈妈
- Mom?
爸爸
Dad?
今天
抱歉
Sorry.
- 本周第二件抢劫案
- Second robbery this week.
- 目击者称劫匪是克莱德 马顿
- The teller I.D.'d clyde mardon as the shooter.
- 什么
- What?
噢 天哪 马顿兄弟回来了吗
Oh, jeez, the mardon brothers are back?
- 发现了什么没
- What do we got?
劫匪抢劫银行 破坏了摄像头
- Perps took the bank, shot out the cameras,
顺便还杀死了那的警卫
And as a chaser, killed the security guard over there.
我让联合国信息服务处的人去挨家挨户调查
I've got unis kicking in doors
与马顿兄弟同伙有关的人
Of known mardon brothers associates.
- 犯罪现场调查科的人来了吗
- Csi been over it?
- 呃 没有
- Uh, no.
- 艾伦哪去了
- Where's allen?
抱歉 抱歉
Sorry, sorry.
-你不能一直罩着他
- You can't keep covering for him.
-犯罪现场调查 借过一下 - 如果他没有过来
- Csi, csi coming through. - If he's not here now,
我就要一个人进行这次调查
I'm gonna have to carry on this investigation without him.
- 抱歉 我迟到了 辛格警长
- Sorry I'm late, captain singh.
- 这回又是怎么了 艾伦先生
- What was it this time, mr. Allen?
你忘记上闹钟了吗
Did you forget to set your alarm clock?
在你回答之前 我先提醒你
Before you answer, I should remind you
你上回的借口是你的车坏了
The excuse you gave last time was car trouble.
想知道为什么我记得这个吗
Want to know why that one was particularly memorable?
- 因为我没有车
- I do not own a car.
- 是我叫他办事去了
- He was running an errand for me.
巴里 我要的东西带来了吗
Barry, did you get me what I asked for?
-对 是的 我带来了
- Yeah, yeah. I did.
就在
I have it right...
在这
Here.
我咬了几口
I had a few bites of it.
超宽的后轮胎
12英寸
12英寸的非对称轮胎印
劫匪乘野马谢尔比GT500款车逃离现场
Getaway car's a mustang shelby gt500.
谢尔比的车轮宽得出奇
Shelby's have a rear super-wide tire
和这个车辙印吻合
Specific to that model.
12英寸的非对称轮胎印
12 inches with an asymmetrical tread.
这还有些别的
And there's something else.
谢了
Thanks.
粪便
Fecal excrement.
我猜是动物的
Animal, I'd guess.
-那支笔是我父亲给我的
- My dad gave me that pen...
在他临终前
Before he died.
- 对不起
- Sorry.
-好了 我准备好看原子轰击器轰击原子了
- Okay, I am ready to see this atom smasher smashing.
- 今天发生枪击案了
- There was a shooting today.
你爸爸需要我处理证据
Your dad needs me to process some evidence,
也就是说我不确定
Which means I don't know if we're going
能不能去科技之星实验室了
To be able to make it to s.T.A.R. Labs.
- 但是去看这东西启动不一直是你的梦想吗
- But seeing this thing turn on is like your dream.
你这个可怜的小书呆子的梦想
Your sad, little nerdy dream.
而且 我为这还取消了今天的约会呢
Besides, I canceled a date for this.
- 别碰我的薯条
- Hands off my fries.
难以置信
Unbelievable.
- 为准备毕业论文 我焦虑得不停的想吃
- I'm stress eating over my dissertation.
我们店销售的可颂甜甜圈
We started selling cronuts at jitters.
我今天吃了两个 如果我不快点毕业
I ate two today. If I don't graduate soon,
我的腰间赘肉要比已婚妇女还要多
I'm gonna be more muffin top than woman.
- 你看起来美极了
- You look amazing.
这个粒子加速器
What is so important
到底有什么重要的地方
About this particle accelerator anyway?
- 哈里森 韦尔斯从事的是有关量子理论的工作
- Harrison wells' work in quantum theory
他们研究出的成果远远领先欧洲核子研究中心
Is light-years ahead of anything they're doing at cern.
- 你在说那个什么东西的时候我听起来简直像鸟语
- You're doing that thing where you're not speaking english.
- 好吧
- Okay.
就是 假设
Just imagine
这个点就是现今为止
That that dot is everything the human race
人类所学习到的所有事情
Has ever learned until this moment.
- 包括搞笑这个词吗
- Does that include "Twerking"?
- 而这个是我们
- That is everything we could learn
能从粒子加速器上学到的
From the particle accelerator.
它让我们通过一种全新的方式来探究物理
It's a whole new way of looking at physics.
完完全全改变了我们思考
It will literally change the way
事物的方式
That we think about everything.
- 你该给自己找个女朋友了
- You got to get yourself a girlfriend.
- 嘿 别缠着他了 他可是在工作
- Hey, leave him alone. He's working.
- 嗨 爸
- Hi, dad.
你的测试结果出来了 - 好的
Your test thingy is done. - Yeah.
我认为马顿兄弟躲在一个农场里
I think the mardon brothers are hiding on a farm.
我在大街上发现的粪便是牛粪
The fecal matter I found on the street, it was cow manure,
含有微量土霉素
Which contained traces of oxytetracycline.
这是种抗菌素
It's an antibiotic.
现在只有四家农场
There are only four farms in the area
还在使用这种抗菌素
That still use it in their feed.
我敢打赌你会发现可爱的小谢尔比停在这四个农场中的一个里
Bet you find a really sweet shelby parked at one of them.
- 爸 既然巴里已经帮你解决了那个便便问题
- Dad, seeing as how barry solved your poop problem,
放我们去科技之星实验室怎么样
How about letting him go to s.T.A.R. Labs?
好吧 去吧 -好耶
- Fine, go. - Yes!
谢谢你 乔
Thank you, joe.
- 那么 巴里 旅途怎么样
- So, barry, how was your trip?
你在星城发现不可思议之事的证据了吗
Did you find proof of the impossible in starling city,
还是仅仅无端地就惹我爸生气了
Or did you just make my dad mad for no reason?
-事实上 当我离开这里时
- Actually, while I was away,
我有机会去思考关于
I had a chance to think about...
你懂的 一些恋爱关系什么的
You know, relationships.
还有 这么说吧 我单身
And, well, I'm not in one.
你也是单身
And you're not in one, either.
而且你是我最好的朋友 艾瑞斯
And you're my best friend, iris.
- 你也是我最好的朋友
- You're mine too.
不然的话我干嘛到这来
Why else would I be here?
- 我不是这个意思 我的意思是
- That's not what I meant. What I...
- 我知道你要说什么 巴里
- I know what you're gonna say, barry.
-我觉得你可能不知道
- I'm not sure you do.
- 即使我们从小住一起
- Even though we pretty much grew up
在同一间屋檐下长大
In the same house together,
我们亲如兄妹
And we're kind of like brother and sister,
但我们又不是真正的兄妹
Because we're not brother and sister,
所以如果和我讨论姑娘们
It can get really weird and awkward
会感到有些奇怪和尴尬
To talk to me about girls.
但我想要你知道
But I just want you to know
可以不用觉得尴尬的
That it shouldn't be awkward.
没人比我更希望
There is nothing that I want more
你遇到那个真命天女
Than for you to meet the right person
完全爱你 倾慕你
That totally loves and adores you
懂得你是多么好的一个男人
For the amazing guy that you are.
- 你说出了我的心里话
- Took the words right out of my mouth.
- 噢 难道你不愿意我这么了解你嘛
- Aw, aren't you glad I know you so well?
- 谢谢你
- Thank you.
我叫哈尔森 韦尔斯
My name is harrison wells.
今晚 我们将迎来全新的未来
Tonight, the future begins.
我和我的团队将要在这做的
The work my team and I will do here
会改变我们对物理学的认知
Will change our understanding of physics.
将推动能源科技的发展
We'll bring about advancements in power,
将推动制药产业的发展
Advancements in medicine,
相信我 那个未来
And trust me, that future
将会比你们想象中还要来的快
Will be here faster than you think.
- 噢 嘿 我的笔记本 里边有我的毕业论文啊
- Oh, hey, my laptop! It's got my dissertation.
- 很抱歉
- I'm sorry.
好吧 小子 你没必要这么做的 是不是
All right, kid, you don't have to do this, all right?
只要把我朋友的包还回来
Just give me back my friend's bag,
我们就既往不咎
And we'll call it even.
好吗
Okay?
-巴里
- Barry!
-你还好吗 -没事
Are you okay? - Yeah.
- 不许动 警察
- Freeze! Police!
或者你想用你的小命尝试一下
Or do you want to find out the hard way
你快还是子弹快吗
You're not faster than a bullet?
- 那个人是谁 他有什么好神气的
- Who is that guy, and what is he so proud of?
就算他抓住了劫匪
So he caught a mugger?
-他是从基斯通调来的
- He's a transfer from keystone.
上任几周了 叫埃迪 斯旺
Started a few weeks ago. Eddie thawne.
- 噢 他就是那个型男探长啊
- Oh, that's detective pretty boy.
我爸爸是这么叫他的
That's what my dad calls him.
他逮捕犯人是很出色
Says he actually keeps score when it comes to arrests.
而且他还很帅
He is pretty though.
- 这是巴里列的单子上的最后一个农场了
- This is the last farm on barry's list.
-听着 我知道这孩子很聪明
- Look, I know the kid's smart,
但是你自己也说过
But you said it yourself.
他有时会疑神疑鬼的
Sometimes he's chasing flying pigs.
- 不管怎样 我们去检查一下吧
- Well, let's check it out anyway.
- 我是琳达 帕金 我们现在就在科技之星实验室外
- I'm linda park, and we're live outside s.T.A.R. Labs
尽管天气恶劣
Despite the inclement weather,
而且还会越变越糟
Which is only going to get worse.
但暴风雨并未
The torrential downpour has in no way affected
影响道粒子加速器
The particle accelerator,
加速器已经启动并运转良好
Which is up and running smoothly
相关报道来自科技之星实验室的首席执行官 哈尔森 韦尔斯
According to s.T.A.R. Labs ceo harrison wells.
天气也
The weather has also...
医生杀妻案
诺拉 艾伦被其丈夫谋杀
- 哇哦  - 是马顿
- Whoa. - Mardon.
啊
Ah!
- 我还要赶飞机呢
- I've got a plane to catch!
- 这他妈的到底
- What the hell?
啊
Ah!
- 查尔 坚持住
- Chyre, hang in there.
- 等等 我们刚刚被告知需要撤离实验室
- Wait, we're now being told to evacuate the facility.
暴风雨可能导致了
The storm may have caused a malfunction
主冷却系统故障
To the primary cooling system.
官方正在试图关闭
Officials are now trying to shut down
粒子加速器 但目前为止
The particle accelerator, but so far,
还未对故障系统完全掌控
Have been unable to regain control of the system...
- 他到底怎么了
- What the hell happened to him?
- 他被闪电劈了
- He was hit by lightning.
- 那他怎么还能活着
- How is he still alive?
- 抬
- Go.
-没有心跳 血常规24 血型和交叉四型
- No heartbeat. Cbc, chem 24, type and cross four.
给他输血 -准备电击
Bag him. - He's coding.
-你不能进来 -我是他亲属
- You can't be in here. - I'm family.
-电压200伏 -巴里
- Charge the paddles to 200. - Barry!
- 离手
- Clear.
闪电侠
第一季 第一集
- 你在干什么
- What are you doing?
- 他喜欢这首歌
- He likes this song.
- 你怎么会知道的
- How could you possibly know that?
- 我看了他的脸谱主页
- I checked his facebook page.
我是说 他能听到周围的声音 对吧
I mean, he can hear everything, right?
- 听觉功能最大的特点在于
- Auditory functions are the last
时刻接受信息
Sensory faculties to degenerate.
- 不能读懂我 不 他不能读懂我的扑克
- Can't read my no he can't read my poker...
噢 我的上帝
oh, my god!
- 我在哪儿 - 他醒了
- Where am I? - He's up.
- 韦尔斯博士 请马上下楼来 马上
- Dr. Wells, get down to the cortex, like, right now.
- 脉搏120 双瞳对光刺激都有反应
- Pulse 120, pupils equally reactive to light.
-看着我 看着我 -嘿嘿 噢 放松
Look at me, look at me. - Hey, hey, whoa, whoa, relax.
没事的 兄弟
Everything's okay, man.
你在科技之星实验室
You're at s.T.A.R. Labs.
- 科技之星实验室 你们是谁
- S.T.A.R. Labs? Who are you?
- 我是思科 雷蒙 她是凯瑟琳 斯诺博士
- I'm cisco ramon. She's caitlin... dr. Snow.
- 我需要你的尿样 尿在这里
- I need you to urinate in this.
- 待会再提这事
- Not this second.
- 发生 发生什么事了
- What is... what is happening? What is going on?
- 你被闪电劈了 哥们
- You were struck by lightning, dude.
-什么
- What?
还给我劈出腹肌了
Lightning gave me abs?
-你的肌肉本该萎缩的
- Your muscles should be atrophied,
但相反地 他们进入了一种
But instead they're in a chronic
无法解释的细胞再生状态
And unexplained state of cellular regeneration.
- 过来 坐这
- Come here. Have a seat.
你一直昏迷着
You were in a coma.
-多久
- For how long?
-九个月
- Nine months.
欢迎醒来 艾伦先生
Welcome back, mr. Allen.
我们有好多事情要讨论
We have a lot to discuss.
- 难以置信我会在这
- It's hard to believe I'm here.
我一直期望能与你面对面
I have always wanted to meet you face to face.
- 是吗
- Yeah?
嗯 你可是费了好大的劲才苏醒过来啊
Well, you certainly went to great lengths to do it.
科技之星实验室的管理并不十分严格
S.T.A.R. Labs has not been operational
因为美国联邦应急管理署
Since fema categorized us
只把我们归类为四等危害机构
As a class four hazardous location.
大猩猩古鲁德
那晚死了17人
17 people died that night.
还有更多的人受了伤
Many more were injured.
我也是其中之一
Myself amongst them.
- 上帝啊
- Jeez.
发生了什么
What happened?
- 9个月前 粒子加速器
- Nine months ago, the particle accelerator
按照计划上线了
Went online exactly as planned.
运行了45分钟 这实现我一生的梦想
For 45 minutes, I had achieved my life's dream.
但是后来 后来机器出现了异常
And then... then there was an anomaly.
电压高得异常
The electron volts became unmeasurable,
实验室下面的底环爆炸了
The ring under us popped.
爆炸释放的能量射向空中
Energy from that detonation was thrown into the sky
然后形成了风暴云
And that, in turn, seeded a storm cloud...
-产生了闪电球
- That created a lightning bolt
劈中了我
That struck me.
- 就是那样
- That's right.
我听说你的事时
I was recovering myself...
正处于恢复阶段
When I heard about you.
每次你心脏骤停的时候
The hospital was undergoing unexplainable power outages
医院总是会突发无法解释的电力中断
Every time you were going into cardiac arrest,
不过那是误诊
Which was actually a misdiagnosis
因为你要知道 你并不是心脏停跳 巴里
Because you see, you weren't flatlining, barry.
而是被闪电劈后你的心跳太快了
Your heartbeat was moving too fast
以至于心电图根本没法记录下来波动
For the ekg to register it.
现在 我不是全城最受欢迎的人了
Now, I'm not the most popular person in town these days,
但是韦斯特侦探和他女儿
But detective west and his daughter
却允许我把你带到这儿来
Gave me permission to bring you here,
在这里我们可以稳定住你的情况
Where we were able to stabilize you.
-艾瑞斯 -艾瑞斯 是的
- Iris? - Iris, yes.
她经常过来看你
She came to see you quite often.
-她太能说话了
- She talks a lot.
- 而且呢 她超性感
- Also, she's hot.
- 我得走了 -不 你不能走
- I need to go. - No, you can't.
不 不 不 凯瑟琳是对的
- No, no. No, caitlin's right.
不 既然你醒了 我们需要多做一些测试
No, now that you're awake, we need to do more tests.
你的身体还在变化
You're still going through changes.
我们不明白的还有很多
There's so much that we don't know.
- 我很好 真的 我感觉很正常
- I'm fine. Really, I feel normal.
谢谢你们救了我
Thank you for saving my life.
就这样吗
Really?
- 这件卫衣我可以留着吗
- Can I keep the sweatshirt?
- 可以 你留着穿这件卫衣吧 - 好的
- Yeah, keep the sweatshirt. - Okay.
- 当然
- Sure.
加满吗 - 谢谢
Fill 'er up? - Thanks.
噢 我的上帝
Oh, my god.
你醒了
You're awake.
科技之星实验室怎么没有打电话给我们
Why didn't s.T.A.R. Labs call us?
- 我刚醒
- I just woke up.
- 你居然可以站起来了
- Should you even be on your feet?
-艾瑞斯 我 我很好
- Iris, I-I'm okay.
- 我看着你死了 巴里
- I watched you die, barry.
你一直都是垂死状态 你的心脏总是停止搏动
You kept dying. Your heart kept stopping.
- 它还在跳呢
- It's still beating.
- 跳得可真快 - 哎哟
- Feels really fast. - Oops.
- 你还好吗 特蕾西
- Are you okay, tracy?
- 没事 我搞定它
- Yeah, I got it.
- 我爸见到你醒来一定会很开心
- My dad is gonna be so happy to see you.
让我去拿一下东西 好吗 我马上回来
Let me get my stuff, okay? Be right back.
- 谢谢你 非常感谢你
- Thank you. Thank you so much.
有什么能为您服务的吗
How can I help you today?
这是一宗抢劫
"This is a robbery."
这是在开玩笑吗
Is this supposed to be a joke?
- 你说呢
- You tell me.
- 噢 你可把我们给吓尿了 孩子
- Oh, you scared the hell out of us, kid.
- 是哟 你午睡睡得可真够久的啊 娃娃脸
- Yeah, that was quite the nap you took there, baby face,
还有你看起来仍然像12岁
And you still look 12.
- 你看起来挺好啊
- You look okay.
真的吗
Are you really?
- 是的 - 韦尔斯探长
- Yeah. - Detective west,
金花旗银行发生抢劫 两人死亡
We've got a 5.15 in progress at gold city bank, two dead.
南边暴雨下的挺猛
Storm's really picking up on the south side.
－我得用你的雨具了
I'd grab your rain gear.
－抱歉 巴里 我得走了
- I'm sorry, barry. I got to run.
- 需要我帮忙吗 - 不 你不用担心
- Do you need my help? - No, you take it easy.
等你安定下来会有好多事要去做
There'll be plenty for you to do once you settle in.
我们走吧 伙计
Let's go, partner.
-嗨 艾伦 见到你真好
- Hey, allen. Glad to see you.
-谢谢 埃迪 -嘿 艾瑞斯
- Thanks, eddie. - Hey, iris.
探长 你该走了
- Detective, you should go.
我爸可不喜欢等人
My dad doesn't like to be kept waiting.
-很高兴你能回归
- Glad you're back.
-在爆炸发生的那个晚上
- The night of the explosion,
克莱德 马顿 枪杀了查尔
Clyde mardon shot and killed chyre.
马顿和他兄弟在逃跑的途中死了
Mardon and his brother died trying to escape.
飞机坠毁
Their plane crashed.
- 艾瑞斯 你有时间吗
- Iris, got a minute?
- 嗨 巴里 见到你真高兴
- Hey, barry. Good to see you.
- 去死吧你
- Screw you!
- 你还好吗
- You okay?
- 我 我还好
- I-I'm fine.
我 我只是需要透透气
I-I just need some air.
晚上再给你打电话 好吗
But I'll call you tonight, all right?
我这是怎么了
What's happening to me?
哦 哦
oh, oh!
棒极啦
Awesome.
你并不相信他能跑那么快 是吧
You don't really believe he can run that fast, do you?
嗯 我相信一切皆有可能
Well, I believe anything is possible,
几分钟之后
And in a few minutes,
说不定你也可以
Maybe you will too.
感觉怎么样 合身吗
How does it fit?
有点紧
It's a little snug.
不过你跑的太快
At least you will be moving so fast
别人也看不到你
No one will see you.
你是不是觉得整个世界都慢下来了
See, you thought the world was slowing down.
其实并不是这样
It wasn't.
你的速度太快了
You were moving so fast
所以其他人就像静止了一样
It only looked like everyone else was standing still.
韦尔士博士将会检查你的能量指数
Dr. Wells will be monitoring your energy output,
凯瑟琳 监视你的器官状况
And caitlin, your vitals.
那你干什么
What do you do?
我制作玩具啊 哥们 检查一下它
I make the toys, my man. Check it.
这是双声道耳机 带有我改良过的相机
This is a two-way headset with a camera I modified.
专门为了抵挡战场上爆炸的声音
Typically designed to combat battlefield impulse noise,
换成你的情况说 可能的音波爆炸
Or in your case, potential sonic booms,
这可真是碉堡了
Which would be awesome.
-干嘛 -没什么
- What? - Nothing.
我注意到你没怎么笑
I just noticed you don't smile too much.
我原本前途无量的生物工程的工作如今毁掉了
My once promising career in bioengineering is over,
我的老板一辈子都得坐轮椅
My boss is in a wheelchair for life,
让你昏迷的那场爆炸
The explosion that put you in a coma
同样也让我未婚夫丧了命
Also killed my fiance.
所以现在我只能是这副表情
So this blank expression kind of feels like the way to go.
艾伦先生 当然我是很想看看
Mr. Allen, while I am extremely eager
你到底有多大的能力
To determine your full range of abilities,
不过我还是建议你克制一点
I do caution restraint.
好
Yeah.
哇
Woo-hoo!
他刚刚的速度超过200码了
He just passed 200 miles per hour.
这不可能
It's not possible.
妈
Mom!
-不 巴里 -妈妈
- No, barry! - Mom!
不 不要让他碰你
- No! Don't let him touch you!
啊
Aah!
这是什么情况
What is all this?
金花旗银行抢劫案的目击者声称
Witnesses from the robbery at gold city bank.
劫匪抢走了20万美金左右
Perp made off with 200 grand, more or less.
-抓住那个家伙 -窗户玻璃飞到了屋里
- Catch these guys. - The windows blew in.
就像龙卷风一样
It was like a hurricane.
大家都躲起来
Everyone ran for cover.
绘图专家会来帮你画图
We're going to have a sketch artist work with you,
如果你可以的话
If you feel up to it.
一个月第三起抢劫案了
Third robbery in a month
每次之前总会下奇怪的暴雨
Where a freak storm precedes it.
听起来有点像
Sounds like one of those "Wide world of weird" Cases
巴里所痴迷的那种神秘世界的案子 -他不是痴迷
Barry's obsessed with. - He's not obsessed.
我猜你没读过他的博客
Guess you haven't read his blog.
银行的摄像头怎么显示
The security cameras at the bank.
很明显它们全被弄短路了
Apparently it all shorted out.
不过我们这里这么多的目击证人
- We got a bunch of witnesses here.
他们都有手机
They all have cell phones.
天慢慢变黑 轰鸣声
- The sky went black and then, boom.
由外及内
Outside was inside.
天啊 看起来就像是一场暴风雨
Man, it was like there was a thunderstorm
出现在银行里
In the bank.
佛科维奇 嫌犯驾驶这黑色的福特野马轿车
Vukuvich, suspect is driving a black mustang.
部分牌照显示是 6KC3
Partial plate six-kilo-charlie-three.
向所有警局发通缉令  -收到
Put out an apb. - Copy that.
看起来你刚刚曾经桡骨远端骨折了
It looks like you had a distal radius fracture.
曾经
Had?
已经自己治愈了 不到三个小时
It's healed... In three hours.
这怎么可能
How is that even possible?
我们不知道 至少到目前为止不知道
We don't know... Yet.
你真该学学怎么停下来
You really need to learn how to stop.
今天发生了什么
What happened out there today?
你本来移动的挺好
You were moving pretty well,
后来有什么东西让你分神了
And then something caused you to lose focus.
我记起了一些东西
I started remembering something.
当我11岁时 我母亲被谋杀了
When I was 11, my mother was murdered.
那时天色很晚
It was late.
我被一阵声音吵醒了
A sound woke me up.
我下了楼梯
I came downstairs and...
看到了一团闪电一样的东西
I saw what looked like a ball of lightning.
闪电里面
Inside the lightning,
有个人
There was a man.
他杀了我妈
He killed my mom.
警察逮捕了我父亲
They arrested my dad.
他现在还在服刑
He's still sitting in iron heights for her murder.
所有人 警察 精神科医生
Everyone, the cops, the shrinks,
他们都告诉我那些都不可能是真的
They all told me what I saw was impossible.
但如果那个杀了我母亲的人
But what if the man who killed my mom
就像我一样呢
Was like me?
嗯 我可以明确的告诉你
Well, I think I can say unequivocally
你是独一无二的
You are one of a kind.
有什么需要帮助的嘛 探长
Can I help you, detective?
你爸在场的时候你就不用
You can stop acting like you can't stand me
装成受不了我的样子了
When your dad's around.
唔
- Aww.
我希望我的男朋友没有被爆头
And I like having a boyfriend who isn't shot to death.
你不能告诉我爸
You can't tell my dad.
他还不知道我和埃迪的事情
He doesn't know about me and eddie.
看来好像还没有人知道这个秘密呢
Doesn't seem like anyone's in on the secret.
我本来就是要告诉你的
I was gonna tell you.
当你在医院的时候
When you were in the hospital,
埃迪支开了我爸爸
Eddie covered my father's shifts
这样我们俩就可以和你呆在一起了
So that we could both be with you.
我请他喝了杯咖啡作为答谢
I thanked him with a cup of coffee,
然后很多事情就这样发生了
And things just kind of happened.
这样也挺好
And it's good.
和自己搭档的女儿约会
Dating your partner's daughter...
这难道不违反部门规定嘛
Isn't that against department regulations?
你怎么这么沮丧
Why are you so upset?
我只是不喜欢对你爸爸撒谎罢了
I just don't like having to lie to your dad, you know?
巴里
Barry?
嘿 马顿
Hey! Mardon!
可怜的人啊
That poor man.
那雾就这样出来了
The way that fog came in,
我从没见过这样的事情
I have never seen anything like it.
巴里 艾瑞斯
Barry! Iris.
我很好 爸
I'm all right, dad.
你到底在想什么
What the hell were you thinking
-把她带到这里来么 -不不不
Having her out here? - No, no, no...
我也告诉过你了 当你见到危险的时候
And I told you, when you see danger,
你赶紧跑远点 你又不是警察
You run the other way. You're not a cop.
-那是因为你不让我当 -你特么说对了
- Because you wouldn't let me. - You're damn right.
乔 我需要和你谈谈
Joe, I need to talk to you.
-等一下 -不 就现在
- It can wait. - No, now.
我知道这是谁干的了
I know who did this.
是克莱德 马顿
It's clyde mardon.
我知道 所有人都以为他死在了
I know everybody thinks he died in a plane crash
科技之星实验室爆炸之后的飞机失事中
After the s.T.A.R. Labs explosion,
但他还活着
But he is alive.
嗯 那晚上一定有什么事情发生了
All right, something happened to him that night.
我觉得他可以控制天气
I...I think he can control the weather.
最近的抢劫案都发生在
The recent robberies, they all happened during
奇怪的天气里
Freak meteorological events.
而当我正对着马顿的时候
And when I just confronted mardon,
大街上立刻就起了雾
The street was instantly enveloped in fog.
当然了 你不会相信我的
Of course you don't believe me.
-你从来都不会相信我 -好吧
- You never believe me. - Okay.
你现在要谈这件事吗
You want to do this now?
就在这 好吧
Out here? Fine.
马顿已经死了
Mardon is dead.
没有人能控制天气 巴里
There is no controlling the weather, barry.
就像那天晚上在你家里
Just like there was no lightning storm
也没有闪电风暴一样
In your house that night.
是你的意识在帮助你这个吓坏了的小男孩
It was your brain helping a scared little boy
接受他所看见的事实
Accept what he saw.
-我爸爸没有杀死我妈妈
- My dad did not murder my mother.
-不 就是他杀的 你父亲杀死了你的母亲
- Yes, he did! Your dad killed your mother, barry!
巴里 我很抱歉 孩子
I am sorry, son!
但是我知道 陪审团也知道
But I knew it, the jury knew it,
现在他为自己所做的付出了代价
And now he's paying for what he did.
-爸爸 够了 -不 艾瑞斯
- Dad, enough! - Unh-uh, iris.
从那天晚上起
I have done my best to take care of you
我尽我最大的能力照顾你
Since that night, and I have never asked
从没有要求任何回报 甚至一句谢谢我也不奢想
For anything in return, not even a thank you,
但现在我一定要要求的是
But what I do ask now is that you
在你的人生中 至少这一次 相信你所看见的世界吧
For once in your life see things as they are.
你是不会相信的
You're not going to believe this.
我们让目击者描述了
We got the eyewitness sketch
抢劫银行的罪犯
Of the robber from the bank job.
如果不考虑别的 这就是克莱德 马顿
If I didn't know better, I'd say that's clyde mardon.
但那是不可能的
But that's impossible.
他死了 对吧
He's dead, right?
我不是唯一一个
I wasn't the only one affected
受到粒子加速器爆炸的影响的 是吗
By the particle accelerator explosion, was I?
-我们不能确定
- We don't know for sure.
-你说过这个城市很安全
- You said the city was safe,
没有其他什么危险了
That there was no residual danger.
但这不是真的 所以 那晚到底发生了什么
But that's not true, so what really happened that night?
嗯
Well...
加速器被激活了
The accelerator went active.
我们都以为自己成了英雄 但是
We all felt like heroes, and then...
所有事情都出错了
It all went wrong.
空间屏障破裂了
The dimensional barrier ruptured,
向我们的世界释放出未知的能量
Unleashing unknown energies into our world.
反物质 暗能量 X元素
Antimatter, dark energy, x-elements...
这些都是理论上的
- Those are all theoretical.
你自己又有多符合理论
And how theoretical are you?
我们绘制了
We mapped the dispersion
穿过市中心和包围市中心的扩散图
Throughout and around central city.
尽管我们也并不知道
Though we have no way of knowing
到底什么 或者是 谁 暴露在辐射中
Exactly what or... Who was exposed,
我们也在寻找
We've been searching for other
其他像你一样的变异人 -变异人
Meta-humans like yourself. - "Meta-humans"?
我们是这么称呼他们的
That's what we're calling them.
我今天看到了一个
I saw one today.
他是抢银行的那个人 他能控制天气
He's a bank robber, and he can control the weather.
越来越酷了
This just keeps getting cooler.
这一点都不酷
This is not cool.
想想看 一个人死去了
All right? A man died.
马顿肯定是通过和我一样的方法 得到了这力量
Mardon must have gotten his powers the same way I did.
通过风暴云
From the storm cloud.
他还在那儿
He's still out there.
我们要在他伤害到别人前阻止他
We have to stop him before he hurts anyone else.
巴里
- Barry!
这是警察的工作
That's a job for the police.
我就是为警察工作的
- I work for the police.
作为一个法庭助理
- As a forensic assistant.
你要为此负责
- You're responsible for this.
为他负责
For him.
重要的是你
- What's important is you!
不是我 我失去了一切
Not me. I lost everything.
我失去了公司
I lost my company.
我的名声
I lost my reputation.
我的自由
I lost my freedom.
之后你摔坏了胳膊
And then you broke your arm,
又三个小时之内痊愈了
And it healed in three hours.
在你体内
Inside your body could be a map
隐藏着通向新世界的地图
To a whole new world... genetic therapies,
疫苗 药物 这些都是宝藏
Vaccines, medicines, treasures buried deep
藏在你细胞中的宝藏 我们不能冒险失去一切
Within your cells and we cannot risk losing everything
只因为你想出去做英雄
Because you want to go out and play hero!
你不是英雄
You're not a hero.
你只是个被闪电击中的年轻人
You are just a young man who was struck by lightning.
我没有
I didn't do this.
我对天发誓 不是我干的
I swear to god, I didn't do this.
爸爸 他们为什么要带走你啊
Dad, why are they taking you?
-巴里 别到房子里去 -妈妈在哪儿
- Barry, don't go in the house. - Where's mom?
-我的儿子会怎样
- What's gonna happen to my son?
-爸爸 -巴里
- Dad! - Barry!
-爸爸 -离房子远点
- Dad! - Stay out of the house!
巴里
Barry!
乔 你认识这些人么
- Joe, you know these people?
我女儿最好的朋友 和她们的孩子
- My daughter's best friends with their kid.
-我很遗憾 -嗯
- I'm sorry. - Mm.
-妈 -巴里
- Mom. - Barry.
- 妈妈
- Mom!
星城
这就是我的故事
So that's my story.
我花了一生时间去追寻不可能的事情
I've spent my whole life searching for the impossible,
从没想过有一天
Never imagining that I would
我也会变成一种不可能
Become the impossible.
那为什么找我
- So why come to me?
我有知觉 你跑600码
Something tells me you didn't just run 600 miles
不仅仅是为了和一个朋友打招呼
To say "Hi" To a friend.
我的一生 都想做更多的好事
- All my life, I've wanted to just do more...
成为更好的人
Be more.
现在我做到了
And now I am.
我第一次有机会帮助别人
And the first chance I get to help someone,
我却把它弄砸了
I screw up.
如果韦尔士博士是对的呢
What if wells is right?
如果我不是英雄呢
What if I'm not a hero?
如果我只是一个被闪电击中的普通人怎么办
What if I'm just some guy who was struck by lightning?
我不认为那道闪电
- I don't think that bolt of lightning
只是随便击中了你 巴里
Struck you, barry.
它选择了你
I think it chose you.
我只是不知道我能不能像你一样 奥利弗
- I'm just not sure I'm like you, oliver.
我不知道我是不是能成为  和平维护者
I don't know if I can be some... Vigilante.
你能做的更好
- You can be better.
因为你能以一种
Because you can inspire people
我永远无法做到的方式激励别人
In a way that I never could...
想守护天使一样 保护着这个城市
Watching over your city like a guardian angel...
改变着它
Making a difference...
化成一道闪电
Saving people...
来拯救人们
In a flash.
跟随你的心声
Take your own advice.
戴上面具
Wear a mask.
酷
- Cool.
真棒
我一直在看在过去的九个月里面
- I've been going over unsolved cases
还没解决的案子
From the past nine months,
我发现
And there's been a sharp increase
离奇死亡和失踪的人数在急剧上涨
In unexplained deaths and missing people.
你们这些变种人可真忙
Your meta-humans have been busy.
我现在不是在怪你们
Now, I'm not blaming you.
我知道你们也不想这些事情发生
I know you didn't mean for any of this to happen.
我也知道你们失去了很多东西
I know you all lost something.
但是我需要你们的帮助来抓住马顿
But I need your help to catch mardon
和那些像他一样的人
And anyone else out there like him.
但是没有你们的帮助的话我做不到
But I can't do it without you.
如果我们决定要做的话
- If we're gonna do this,
我有一些可能会派上用场的东西
I have something that might help.
一些我一直在研究的东西
Something I've been playing with.
设计它是为了取代
Designed to replace the turnouts
传统消防服
Firefighters traditionally wear.
我想如果科技之星实验室能够为人们做一些好的事情
I thought if S.T.A.R. Labs could do something nice
也许他们就不会
For the community, maybe people wouldn't
太生韦尔斯博士的气了
Be so angry at dr. Wells anymore.
它有什么用
- How is it going to help me?
它的表面加强了三聚合物
- It's made of a reinforced tri-polymer.
能够耐高温还有耐磨
It's heat and abrasive resistant,
所以它可以承受得起你的
So it should withstand your moving
高速移动
At high-velocity speeds.
还有这个气动设计
And the aerodynamic design
应该可以帮助你控制你的速度
Should help you maintain control.
再加上 它有内置的传感器
Plus, it has built-in sensors
那么 我们可以跟踪你
So we can track your vitals
随时和你保持联系
And stay in contact with you from here.
谢谢
- Thanks.
现在 我们如何找到马顿
Now how do we find mardon?
我重新布设科技之星实验室的卫星
- I retasked S.T.A.R. Labs satellite
检测中心城区
To track meteorological abnormalities
的气候异常
Over central city.
刚刚有阵脉冲
We just got a ping.
大气压在几秒钟之间
Atmospheric pressure dropped 20 millibars
就下降了20毫巴
In a matter of seconds.
我跟踪到它在城西的农场
I've tracked it to a farm just west of the city.
我没说马顿还活着
- I'm not saying mardon is alive.
但如果他还活着的话 这是
But if he was, this is the last place
他和他弟弟最不可能躲的地方
Him and his brother hid out.
我们走吧
Let's go.
马顿
Mardon?
跪下
On your feet.
把手放到头上
Hands on your head.
你逮到我了
- You got me.
狂风暴雨的那晚 在科技之星实验室被摧毁
The night of the storm, after s.T.A.R. Labs blew,
我们的飞机坠毁之后
After our plane went down,
我醒来躺在地上 还活在
And I woke up on the ground alive,
当我知道我拥有的能力之后 我明白了
When I saw what I can do, I understood.
我是上帝
I am god.
把你的臭嘴闭上
- Shut the hell up.
转身
- Turn around.
你觉得你的枪可以阻止上帝么
- Do you think that your guns can stop god?
为什么他妈的上帝要去抢劫银行
- Why in the hell would god need to rob banks?
你说得对
- You're right.
我过去的想法太胆小
I've been thinking too small.
巴里 巴里
- Barry! Barry!
这个东西越来越靠近了
This thing's getting closer.
风速每小时200英里 而且还在继续上升
Wind speeds are 200 miles-per-hour and increasing.
巴里 你能听到我的声音吗
Barry, can you hear me?
可以 非常清楚
- Yeah. Loud and clear.
如果继续加速 它会形成五级龙卷风
- If it keeps up, this could become an f-5 tornado.
并且将席卷城市
- But it's headed towards the city.
我如何阻止它 兄弟
How do I stop it? Guys?
我让它解体行不行
What if I unravel it?
你想怎么做
- How the hell are you going to do that?
我绕它反向跑
- I'll run around it in the opposite direction,
阻止它增大
Cut off its legs.
要这样做速度必须保持每小时700英里
- He'd have to clock 700 miles-per-hour to do that.
你的身体可能承受不了这样的高速
- Your body may not be able to handle those speeds.
你会死的
You'll die.
我必须试一下
- I have to try.
战斗服撑住了
The suit's holding up.
-他可能撑不住 -他可以的
- But he's not. - He can do it.
我知道他可以的
I know he can do it.
风暴太强大了
It's too strong!
是时候实现我的野心了
- It's time to think big.
你可以做到的 巴里
- You can do this, barry.
你说得对
You were right.
我要为这所有负责
I am responsible for all of this.
这么多的人因为我
So many people have been hurt
而受到伤害 当我看着你的时候
Because of me, and when I looked at you,
我看到的 是一个因我傲慢自大而被牵连的无辜受害者
All I saw was another potential victim of my hubris.
是的 是我造成的这场灾难
And yes, I created this madness,
但你 巴里 你可以阻止它
But you, barry, you can stop it.
你可以做到的
You can do this.
现在 跑 巴里 快跑
Now run, barry, run!
巴里
- Barry?
嘿
- Hey.
我没想过还会有人像我一样
I didn't think there was anyone else like me.
我跟你不一样
- I'm not like you.
你是杀人犯
You're a murderer.
-巴里 -一切都结束了
- Barry? - It's over.
我没事
I'm okay.
为何你可以做到
- What you can do...
是因为闪电球吗
It was the lightning bolt?
差不多
- More or less.
抱歉 巴里
- I'm sorry, barry.
我很抱歉 我之前竟不信你
I'm sorry I didn't believe you.
我曾认为你调查那些不可能发生的事是疯了
And I called you crazy for chasing the impossible.
但你妈妈去世那晚
But you really did see something
你的确看到了什么
That night your mom died.
而你父亲是无辜的
And your dad is innocent.
我要你答应我
I need you to promise me something.
不要告诉艾瑞斯
I don't want you telling iris
你的能力 一点都不要提
About anything you can do, any of it.
我想保证她的安全
I want her safe.
答应我
Promise me.
好的
- Yeah.
嘿 猛男
Hey, slugger.
从我11岁以来你一直这么叫我
You've been calling me that since I was 11.
有趣的是 我今天终于
- Funny thing is, I finally got
去战斗了
Into a fight today.
你刚刚从昏迷中醒来
- You just got out of a coma.
我不确定你应该参与战斗
I'm not sure you should be picking fights.
嘿
Hey...
你赢了吗
Did you win?
是的 我赢了
- Yeah, I did.
你没有杀死妈妈
- You didn't kill mom.
你知道我知道的 对吧
You know I know that, right?
有你相信我就足够了
- You believing me is all I need.
你很快就能出狱了
- You're not gonna be in here much longer.
无论谁杀了妈妈
Whoever killed mom...
无论谁杀了她
Whatever killed her...
我想我终于有办法可以找到他们
I think I finally have a way to find them.
阻止他们
To stop them.
巴里 我们已经讨论过这个问题
- Barry, we've talked about this.
是时候放手了
It's time to let it go.
你别再担心我
You have got to stop worrying about me,
照顾好你自己
And live your life.
我第一次感到我终于有能力查清这件事
- For the first time, I feel like I finally can.
事实上 自从那晚妈妈去世后
The truth is, ever since the night mom died,
我始终放不下想不开
I've been stuck in one place,
因此错过了生活中许多美好的事
Missed out on a lot of things.
但我今非昔比
But I'm different now.
我交了些新朋友
I've made some new friends.
他们帮助我找到了方向
They're helping me find my way...
为什么它的形状像闪电球
- Why is it shaped like a lightning bolt?
因为好玩啊
- So it's not boring.
我终于能变强并前进了
- To finally move forward.
你还记得吗 你曾要求我改名
You remember when you wanted me to change my name
为了避免别人知道你是我爹而找我麻烦
So I wouldn't have to deal with people knowing you're my dad?
现在 我很高兴他们知道你是我爹
I'm glad they know.
能成为你儿子 我感到很荣耀
I'm so proud to be your son.
我爱你 儿子
- I love you, son.
我也爱你 爸
- I love you too, dad.
我叫巴里 艾伦
My name is barry allen,
我是世上跑得最快的人
And I am the fastest man alive.
我的朋友最近给我
A friend recently gave me
取了个新名字
The idea for a new name.
我有预感 它会火
And something tells me, it's gonna catch on.
闪电侠消失的危机
2024年  4月  25号